[music]
>> Welcome to this new episode of under
hood. So today we are going to talk
about something a little bit different.
We are not actually going to talk about
the product by itself, but something
that
is still
about AI.
We're talking we're going to talk about
benchmarking.
And today with me I have Håkon. Hello.
Hi.
>> How are you? Um I'm doing great. So
>> [clears throat]
>> the subject of of this podcast today is
BC Bench. Yes. So Håkon, tell us a
little bit what is BC Bench?
BC Bench is a offline evaluation
framework
that measures how coding agents performs
on real world engineering tasks in
Business Central or AL programming
language.
Um it is very heavily inspired by Sweep
Bench. Mhm. Uh that's a paper published
about 2 years ago that measures
different AI models capability
on real world Python tasks.
We adopted their methodology for well
Business Central and AL to help us
answer questions like um if a model
perform better than others in AL tasks
or if we can provide custom instructions
or different tooling to improve the
coding agents performance on
real world tasks we face
day-to-day. All right, we'll get much
more in into the detail of this, but
just so um
uh
so people understand this this is not a
something we implemented in the product,
right? This is not a feature. No. Uh
this is about measuring
um how good the deep the energetic
experience is when you do AL
development. Exactly.
>> Right? So it's it's actually a tool to
figure out um
what models can do
for helping AL developers. Is that
correct? Exactly. Imagine we get a bug
report for a feature we developed and
instead of
uh we fix the bug ourselves, we ask the
agent coding agent to implement the fix
for us and this is the scenario we're
evaluating here. It's not something
that's part of the product
but more for developers in the Visual
Studio Code environment. So we started
we started looking at this because we
realized that there's a lot of people
obviously today that are using agent and
and and and models and and Copilot and
GitHub Copilot to write AL code, right?
>> Yes. Uh and we have a if you recall we
we we we had a video not too long ago
with Stefan where we show uh
how you could do vibe coding in in AL.
And
so in you know looking at realizing that
there's actually a lot of people vibe
coding also in AL,
we we started thinking okay maybe we
should try to do something to improve
these
these this experience for our
developers. And that's where BC Bench
come in. So we'll we'll get into
some of the details and more into what
you know what's behind all this, but
before um
you mentioned that
before you do that you mentioned that BC
Bench was largely inspired by Sweep
Bench. So maybe we can start by you know
explaining a little bit what is Sweep
Bench. Uh Um
Sweep Bench is a
a
benchmark framework that's very similar,
but their focus is on evaluating
models capabilities for Python
repositories.
So
the methodology is what we followed
here.
>> It's an open source Yes. thing, right?
It's not something that Microsoft does.
It's it's an open source project, right?
>> Yes. It is
used by
the big model providers like Anthropic,
OpenAI and Google
and that's why we choose this specific
framework to follow. Mhm. So it's a it's
a very popular benchmark that as you
mentioned you know the big you know
model company are using and and the
results are actually public and you can
see you know
what model is doing best in Sweep Bench,
right?
>> Yes. Uh so so tell us a little bit about
the the methodology then. Yes. Um
I think it's a very smart method they
developed. So what they did is they go
to GitHub and find some popular Python
repositories.
Uh they find
previous pull requests done by human
engineers
that fix
an issue. Mhm.
Um
and introduce some tests union tests to
verify their fix.
Uh the um
gave the exact same issue and the same
code base to a coding agent instead
and asked the coding agent to generate a
fix. And how do we know if the fix is
correct or not? We run the original
union test introduced by humans
to verify if the fix is correct and if
the test pass, then we count that
uh fix is correct. If not, then it's a
failure attempt. Uh and
and yeah that's the methodology we
followed exactly for BC Bench here as
well.
So you saw that so you you saw that
Sweep Bench methodology and that
inspired you in creating something from
its equivalent for AL. Exactly. Can you
could you reuse some of the code from
from from Sweep Bench some of the things
that is in the in in in this open source
project? Um as a matter of fact we did.
So
there is a few differences here.
Sweep Bench is focused on Python code
repositories and we are AL. Mhm. And we
use uh
Azure DevOps internally. So our code
base is hosted a bit differently,
but we also have this BC Apps repository
on GitHub publicly available. So there
we managed to reuse some of the code
from Sweep Bench to to crawl the code
base and find the pull requests that we
need for our data set.
Uh but yeah we have to adopt something
for the uh ADO and how to run tests. We
have to have our own scripts. We're
actually using AL Go and BC Container
Helper to help us run tests and get the
result. So that was most of the work you
had to do to create BC Bench was to
uh adapt and and make and and do the
things that you just mentioned. Exactly.
Yeah, we have to Yeah, the whole program
language is different. So um
uh the infrastructure side of the work
is to uh figure out how to run tests
reliably in a pipeline
and also
about the goals. We want is to make this
public to well
everyone. Uh so we have to build the
whole pipeline on github.com directly.
So one day hopefully we'll make it
public.
So
okay so so what
what tell tell us a little bit more
about the methodology for AL then.
You know it's it's not it's not exactly
the same then for Sweep Bench. It's
inspired for it, but tell us a little
bit what what we do for AL. Yeah.
Um
So majority of the part is the same
where we we go to our internal
repository. We find the bug reports.
Obviously this time will be on Azure
DevOps.
Uh and then we collect them into a
problem statement what we call here in
each task that
uh is what we will send to the coding
agent to implement and then we store a
what is called a base commit to
represent the state of the code base to
make sure the coding agent has the exact
same context as the human engineer who
solved it in the first place. So
basically we if I understand correctly
we kind of
go back in time Exactly. to the the
point
where the code base
was at the particular moment where the
bug was detected.
And by the way we focus mostly on bugs,
right? Whereas Sweep Bench is all sorts
of issues, right? It's not only bugs, is
it? I think they also primarily focus on
bugs.
>> Okay. So so so that's in that matter
that's kind of the same. Yes. So we we
find a bug back in time and we kind of
recreate we use a time machine and
>> [laughter]
>> recreate the the environment as it was
at at at at that at that particular
time. So like the human as you mentioned
like you mentioned it, right? Yes. And
that's what we gave to the to the agent
and asked the agent to
to solve that bug, right?
>> Yes. So now instead of the human, we ask
the agent now you solve it. Yeah. And
then we look at the result, right? So
that's how that's how we created our
data set. Uh yes. Or or tested or
whatever you call it.
>> Yes. Yes. That's how we
we collected the through looking through
all the internal engineers working in
our repository. We have
good data set there. So how many do we
have right now? How many do we have in
our data set? Uh last time I checked is
66 tasks in the data set.
Well obviously the number is growing
every day. We're looking through the
repository every single day.
Um [clears throat] so
maybe more now, but yeah. Why why can't
we just pick any bug because we have
plenty of bugs. We have more than 66 I'm
sure I'm sure you know.
>> [laughter]
>> So why why not take you know just the
last 100 bugs or something like that or
200 bugs? That's a good question. So
when we collect the data set we have a
few criterias on what can we collect. Uh
one of the criteria is
it's a pull request must be resolving
exactly one bug.
So so we know this PR is fixing
this specific issue. So we don't confuse
the agent with
too many things. Another criteria is
that the bug must have all the context
it needed to solve to be solved.
>> Mhm. Because in many scenarios we found
the engineers kind of have everything in
their head. They don't write it down. So
it's a bit unfair to ask coding agent to
solve without the full picture. So there
might be some bugs where there's very
little description of what the bug is,
but people just know that it's a bug.
>> Exactly.
>> So it's not it's not and the agent
doesn't know.
Exactly. We have found many scenarios
where there is just one line in the bug
that
it doesn't really reflect what the bug
actually
>> it fair to say that since that agents
are not quite capable of doing the same
work as human yet? Yes, I think so
because I think the current workflow we
have lots of context are in
well, human interactions and
Teams chat and things like that.
>> [clears throat]
>> But we still able to find so that we we
focus on the bugs and that's why it's a
little bit difficult to
it takes some time let's say to to
create this data set where we have to go
through our
our code base and and our our history of
bug fixing and find the good bugs that
fulfill the criteria you mentioned,
right?
>> Exactly. And
there's a lot more criteria here for
example one important case here is the
fix the test must not have dependency on
the fix.
So that's actually one thing happens
very often when we say we make a fix
that throw a error in the code base and
then the fix the test will be to verify
the error is correctly thrown with the
correct error message. So in this case
test have a dependency on the fix
meaning the error message has to be
exact match.
Then it's a bit unfair to ask the agent
to create a fix as well because any
change in the error message will produce
a a fake false positive. Yeah.
Okay.
So so what
what what can we benchmark with with BC
bench? Now we have these 66 or so bugs
and we run that through through the
agent through the agent and basically
what it does is it goes through each of
them and try to fix the bugs. Yes.
>> And then we get like a scoring
for these and so what what can we what
can
what type of benchmark can we run? Yes,
we can measure differences between
different models. See if model A is
better than model B. And if we control
the if we fix the model then we can run
different benchmarks on if we provide
one MCP server if that increase the
performance of the coding agent or we
can And that tooling, you know, give
some more tools to the basically in
essence give more tools to the agent
with for the same model we fix the model
as you mentioned I would say okay you
run on you know, GPT something
and then then you say okay now you have
no tools for example or try to fix that
bug or you have this set of tools
and try to feed that bug again same bug,
right? So what can what kind of tools
are we talking about here?
So we are currently focusing on tool
that built by our developer experience
team
that's called
AL2 MCP server.
The idea here is to bring all the tools
we build in VS code extension the AL
language extension and provide the same
set of two
or a subset of the tools to the coding
agent through the MCP server like
compile
finding symbols and maybe running tests
and things like that. So we want to know
if the coding agents actually perform
better with those new set of tools. So
that's that's kind of one of the biggest
motivation for for this effort and
having BC bench because we'll know that
we we we are going to invest into
adding more tools to to the Visual
Studio code experience
but it's very difficult if without a
benchmark to figure out whether you
know, is this actually going to help the
agents? Now we actually can put numbers
on it and put metric on it, right? We
can say if we add this tool we can see
what the effect of it is, right? So do
do we have any can we say already today
that you know, when adding some of the
tools we we we help the agent and we got
better results?
Well, the the short answer is not
conclusively.
We we run them we actually did a
rigorous analysis on on this AL2 MCP
server. We run multiple times and try to
measure if the accuracy improved. We did
see an increase on the average accuracy
or what we call resolution rate. But
there is a overlap on the confidence
interval. So we cannot [clears throat]
claim that the the tools we're building
made it better.
But I think this is a very significant
result as well
because it highlights the purpose of BC
bench. We want to be able to do an
experiment and iterate on the design of
the tooling and see the number keeps
getting better. And actually that's
exactly what we did with the new result
we got. We provided some feedback to the
developer experience team and now we
have a new version of AL2 MCP server. So
hopefully we can see a better result
there. So basically what you're saying
in other words that before we didn't
know we
can maybe try a few examples but it's
not very scientific. Now we actually
know for sure because we have a very
scientific way to measure the effect of
these tools with which basically a
statistical method, right? When we run
these things several times and and look
at the variance and things like that. So
we can actually say with a you know,
good confidence
whether that helps or not, right?
Exactly. So that's that's that's great
because that that that they all also
prioritize. If we figure out this tool
doesn't make any difference then we
don't need to support it anymore and
then we can focus our effort on some
other improvement for for the SDK
experience, right? Exactly. I think
there's many ideas to provide various
tools to the agent and then with this
well, experimentation we can figure out
which tools are you actually useful for
the coding agent and which tools we
don't need to spend time on.
Okay, that's great. So what what other
things can we vary when we run the base?
So you mentioned we can
try different models different tooling
what what else can we can we can we vary
in the benchmark runs? We can also vary
the what we call agent harness. So we
can try different coding agents. At the
moment we have two coding agents.
The first one is what we call a mini BC
agent. That's inspired by
the same author of sweep bench to build
a mini sweep agent. With very very
minimum agent scaffold with 100 Python
100 lines of Python code. And we build
another 100 lines of Python code on top
and produced
a mini BC agent
that have access to only PowerShell and
nothing else
and calling endpoint
Microsoft foundry.
So that's one agent. We have another
agent that's GitHub copilot that we use
day-to-day. So we can compare between
those two agent if the
GitHub copilot agent actually makes
things better.
We have
>> be clear that's not the same agent that
you're using in Visual Studio code, is
it? No, it is a well, it's similar to
GitHub copilot in Visual Studio code but
designed for to be running in terminal
and in pipeline environment.
Yeah, so we can vary different coding
agents. We can also vary in different
custom instructions. So we can provide
explanation on what AL is, what
syntax looks like and try if that makes
coding agent perform better.
We can also do the latest addition is
the skills are a new thing addition to
GitHub copilot. So we can try if
providing
skills.md
will improve the coding agent's
performance. Just to just to be clear we
actually need so it's not we don't
when we do the the benchmarking and ask
the
the models of the AI to solve these bugs
it's we we do need a kind of an agent,
right? It's not enough to have just the
model because you need to have something
that say okay, here is here are the
instructions, here's what you need to
do, here is what you take, you know, is
what the things you're allowed to do for
as you mentioned you can write
PowerShell. So this is actually kind of
a small agent, right? So it's not enough
to to just have the model. You want you
want the the benchmark to perform a
certain task so you need to have you
know, an orchestration of a small
orchestration. It's not it's a small
agent but it's still a an agent of some
kind, right? And so what you mentioning
before is that the two agent that we can
we can basically plug in the benchmark.
So we can run with one and one and one
with the other and kind of compare what
what effect it has, right? Yes.
All right, so
now that we
that we can have all these measurement
Um,
can you tell us a little bit about what
what we are going to do with it? What's
the next, you know,
what's the next development of PC agent?
Well, how are we how are we going to
further improve it?
Um, for the PC bench framework, we have
some [clears throat] planned
improvements on
bringing more categories to PC bench.
Uh, so currently we are focusing on bug
fixing
this scenario. Um, hopefully we have
much more work as a software engineer.
We want to bring test generation. Um,
so giving a a bug report, we want to ask
the coding agent to generate a test
that reproduce the bug.
Uh, we also want to
build a a category called code review.
So now,
with the help of coding agent, we are
producing more and more pull requests.
So
we need some help to review those pull
requests as well.
Um, for the coding agent part, I think
there will be improvements from
developer experience team to
bring
additional toolings. I think the next on
the list is to run tests
uh, through the MCP server to ask to
allow coding agent to iterate on the
code it generated by the agent itself.
They would be typically they would so
what we expect the agent to do is they
they would try to do a fix
and then they would be able as opposed
of today today they they do they kind of
working in a blind if you compare to a
software engineer, right? Yes. They the
agents, I mean they they try to produce
a fix and
and they they don't they can't actually
run the fix against the tests, right?
Whereas if we gave the agent the ability
to to run to run the fix against the
test, you know, we hope that
that it would be
most likely better at at solving because
that's how human work, right? They they
you you would you know, that's how
a developer would work. You would try to
write a fix, run the test and then if
the test fails, you would go back and
try to to adjust the you know, the fix
to to make the test pass and our our
expectation that agent would be would be
doing exactly that, right? And be and
and and hence getting better at at
solving
coding task, right? Exactly. So I think
that's a very fair hypothesis to make
and that's why we have PC bench too.
After we produce this tool to run tests,
then we can use PC bench to verify the
result to see if our assumptions are
correct or not. So what we would what we
would expect we would see with that for
example, in that in that very particular
example is with that the ability to run
test
we would get say resolution of say a 40%
or something and and then so the agent
would be meaning the agent would be able
to resolve 40% of the bugs, but then if
we gave the ability to to the agent to
run test, we would expect that this
number would increase to you know, 50 60
maybe more who knows, we'll see.
Exactly. But if it doesn't, that means
that the agent doesn't need to run test,
which I would be surprised with the
result, but
but you know, we we'll see, you know,
we'll see.
But that will also probably give a very
good indication that
if we allow if we if we implement that
ability to run tests in the Visual
Studio Code experience, right? That all
developers will get a much better
agentic coding vibe slash vibe coding
experience because the agent will do the
same most likely. It will go and you
know, the GitHub Copilot agent in in VS
Code will go and also run the tests you
have in your in your environment and
hopefully do a much better job at
performing various uh
software engineering task. Yes, I think
that's one of the assumption we made in
PC bench is that if a agent with a
certain setup perform well in PC bench
then it means with a similar setup in
Visual Studio Code, the experience will
be the similar produce similar result.
Yeah.
So by the way, we we didn't mention
that, but what does
what does SWE bench stand for? Uh,
that's SWE bench.
I think that's short for a software
engineer. Yeah. And yeah, I think that's
yeah, what
big model providers use that to
measure their models' capability on
software engineering tasks in So that's
yeah, that's the
the ground the ground concept
the basic idea, right? And so this is
natural that so we started with bugs and
then you mentioned before that we are
going to evolve PC bench to
to have more you know, more tasks like
tasks like
you mentioned
adding tests for example, which is also
a software engineer task.
So the idea is to have more and more
software engineering tasks added to the
bench and and measure and in that sense
we can measure the ability of
agents who to do perform software
engineering task Yes. and help
programmers and developers to to to
to have a better agentic coding
experience, right? Yes. So we yeah, the
test generation, code review, we also
have code refactoring on the agenda and
potentially feature addition. So instead
of fixing a bug, we ask the agent to
implement a full feature instead and
that would be exciting to see what would
the result be. So that's pretty
ambitious. Yeah, very much because I
think the challenge would be how to
evaluate
if the a feature is correct or not.
>> Yeah, how do Yeah, it's pretty hard
because there might be so one thing is a
bug is you know, a bug is and that's
that's why we started there because a
bug is really straightforward. We have a
test that fails, you know, after the
test pass. If you have a full feature
um, it can be a little bit difficult to
evaluate with a for example, you know,
we might have
um,
uh, let's say the the the the agent
choose to to create pages, you know, and
then the pages, you know, they might not
look like they should be looking like or
you know, there might be things that
it's a little bit hard for the
for the agent to verify that kind of
thing or do we plan on adding also the
ability to to do that?
Oh.
I think that's a bit
uh,
probably in the future. We haven't
really thought about that yet. Yeah. But
that's but that's not unrealistic. Maybe
there is a future where you know, you
can you have agent they they can
actually run code, but they can also
look at the pages.
I mean our our agent runtime
which we you know,
talk about in some other videos actually
is doing that looking at pages at PC
pages in a certain way. So you could
imagine that
maybe we could do something like that,
but that's more in the future. We are we
are a little bit you know, speculating
and but why not? Who knows? That could
be a good idea actually.
So
so we we did run against various models.
So what are the results? Which models
are
performing the best as of today? Yes. So
we we found that
Cloud Opus 45 is the best model we have
access
so far and it outperforms than any other
models we have access to through GitHub
Copilot
and that's kind of
not too big a surprise here because
there is similar results people are
seeing on SWE bench
on Python tasks.
Uh, but
So what we see actually if I recall
correctly, if we look at the ranking of
the models in SWE bench, like which
model are performing the best like
there's like a ranking.
We'll put a we'll put the link in the in
the comments, you can look it up
yourself. Um,
the the ranking we see for for PC bench
is more or less the same, isn't it? Yes.
Yes. And that's So that's that's
comforting. What it means, but it wasn't
it wasn't a given from the start, right?
No. But what it means is that
these models are
you know, the way they they can handle
Python, but they're just as good with
AL.
Yes. Um, But would you know that before
you before PC bench, we didn't know
that. Now we can see there is you know,
there is more or less you know,
equivalence between
you know, handling writing code in
Python and writing code in AL, which you
know, we we actually have been wondering
a little bit about that for a while
because
there's a lot of you know, everybody
knows that LLMs and models they they
train you know, on looking at what's on
the internet.
And obviously there is a lot of Python
code on internet, a lot more Python code
than than AL code. There's not that much
AL code out there, right?
So you know, it's not it's not given
that they would be as good as writing AL
than they are writing Python because
they've seen a lot more they've seen a
lot more Python than they've seen AL.
But it seems that you know, it seems
that actually they are you know, just as
good as Python and they are at AL. So
that's that's good that's comforting.
That's good that's a good news in in in
in a sense, right?
We yeah, we didn't know the result. We
we kind of make the assumption, but we
never know.
We actually looked up the data on
GitHub. Mhm. There are more than 2
million public Python repositories out
there too. That's a that's a lot.
Repositories. Yes, repositories. Which
is might contain millions of line of
code potentially, right? And there are
300 something AL
public repositories out there. So there
is a very big difference.
>> Huge difference, yeah. Yeah. So
but it's good to know that the results
kind of correlates between those two.
Yeah.
So we we right now we are running all
these benchmarking internally.
Um mid can So what you know what
uh
what about our partners and developers?
Is that you know is that something that
they could benefit of? Uh you know BC
Bench is that something they could use?
Yeah, definitely. Um I think there are
kind of two sides uh to that question.
Uh the first part is we aim to make BC
Bench public. Um well, first of all a
bench benchmark is not
uh useful unless people can reproduce
the result.
>> Mhm. So we aim to make it public so
everyone our partner community can
reproduce the result.
And also they can everyone can run their
own instructions or their own toolings
to verify if they actually works uh
through BC Bench. Uh what we see is
there is many efforts from our partner
community uh building great MCP servers
and the best practices and things like
that. Um now with BC Bench they can
verify if it helps in solving what bugs
in AL. Mhm. So they could take our own
benchmark BC Bench and they could um you
know take the their own MCP server if
they have if they have done some things
around this and see if that you know
helps in any way uh in the in the agent
coding experience, right? Yeah, that
would be great. It would be cool.
>> Would they be able to run these on their
own code as well? That brings me to the
second part. Yes. So um
a BC Bench uh is a evaluation harness.
Uh what um
we want to do is that we will want to
create a partner data set. Mhm. Where
partners can simply plug in this own uh
their own code base in in the data set
and replace all our Microsoft data to
make sure that whatever coding agency is
performing in Microsoft code base is
similar to what partners are
experiencing on their code base as well.
So yes, that's part of the plan as well.
All right. So yeah, something to look
forward to. Uh be able to play around
with our BC Bench. Thank you Erhard.
That was That was very cool and thank
you for for for joining this this this
video and thank you for watching.